#Encodergasm Presents
～
Hey, did you do that by yourself?
（タルカン）あんた
それ １人でやったの？
Pretty good!
大したもんだ
おおっと 仲良くしようぜ
Hey, let's be amiable.
We shouldn't waste what our whimsical god has given us.
せっかくの神様の気まぐれを
無駄にすることはない
God?
（ウダイ）神？
Or rather, for these guys, it would be the devil.
こいつらにとっちゃ悪魔かな
飲むかい？ ドンペリだぜ
Want some?  It's Dom Perignon.
（ウダイ）乾杯だ
悪魔に魅入られた この船に
Cheers.
To this ship that has charmed the devil.
（フェイ）
一体 どうなってんのよ
ここのシャワーときたら
What in the world is going on with the showers in this place?!
This is the fourth time!  The FOURTH time!
これで もう４回目よ ４回目
Even Buddha gets upset after the third time!
仏の顔だってね 三度で怒んのよ
Hey, are you listening?
ちょっと聞いてんの？
The shower broke, and only cold water comes out.
（ジェット）
シャワーが壊れて水しか出ない
蛇口受けが落ちてきた
And the faucet fell off.
If you know about it, fix it!
（フェイ）分かってんだったら
早く直してよ
取り込み中だ
I'm busy right now.
You can do THAT any time you want...
（フェイ）
そんなもん いつだって…
（ジェット）うん？
We're busy!
Don't just hang up!  What if it's an emergency?
（ジェット）勝手に切るな
急用だったらどうする？
ふふん
分かったよ　直しゃ いいんだろ？
Oh, all right.  You'll be happy if I fix it, right?
（フェイ）はい 後でかけ直すわ
名前は？
Hi, he'll call you back.  What's your name?
OK, Fad.  I'll tell him.
ＯＫ ファドね　伝えるわ
ファド？
Fad?
ファドだって？
Did you say Fad?
It's not hot?
熱くないの？
Why don't you fix that?
いい加減 治せば？
直すって言ったろ
I told you I'll fix it.
No, your arm.
その手よ
I mean, reconstructive surgery doesn't cost that much nowadays, right?
再生手術なんて 今どき
大した値段じゃないでしょう？
This ship is my ship.
（ジェット）この船は俺の船だ
この腕も俺の腕だ
And this arm is my arm.
Don't tell me what I need to do.
口出しは やめろ
Now, you death row inmates.
（ディグ）さあて 死刑囚の皆さん
残念ながら―
I'm sorry to say, but the cruise to the prison on Pluto has been canceled.
冥王星刑務所クルーズの旅は
中止です
（ディグ）本船は これより
ミステリーツアーに入りまして…
This ship will now enter a mystery tour...
What are you going to do?
（パイロット）どうするつもりだ？
Do you think this ship is enough for you to escape?
この船だけで
逃げきれると思うのか？
I wasn't talking to you...
おめえには言ってねーよ
む 無駄なことはやめて
おとなしく投降すれば…
S-Stop wasting your time like this.
If you surrender peacefully...
I told you to shut up.
（ディグ）
黙ってろって言ってんだよ
（エルロイ）
カッカすんなよ ディグ
Don't get so hotheaded, Dig.
あーあ 大事な人質が
台なしじゃないか
Oh, man... there goes our precious hostage.
I'm not letting anyone tell me what to do.
俺に指図は させねえ
文句のあるやつは
今すぐ出てこい！
If you got a problem with that, step forward!
YOU!
てめえ！
はっ！ 思い出した
I remember...
You're... yeah...
あんた 確か…
組織の殺し屋のウダイ
That assassin for the syndicate...
Udai.
Caught you red-handed tossing a cigarette butt.
（ファド）ポイ捨ての現行犯だ
That would be a fine of 20000 woolongs, Jet.
２万ウーロンの罰金だな ジェット
フン
Then I'll need to collect that loan I gave you...
それなら お前に貸してあった金に
７年分の利子がついて―
...with 7 years' worth of interest, to cover it... and then some.
お釣りがくるな
When did you buy me that coffee?
いつのコーヒー代だ？
そんなのは とっくに時効だよ
That's long past the statute of limitations!
So you still think you're a gunman with a gun like that?
相変わらず そんな銃で
ガンマン気取りか？
Ｉ.Ｓ.Ｓ.Ｐも税金の無駄遣いだ
Sure is a waste of ISSP tax money.
これがか？
This is?
No, your salary.
お前の給料だよ
Yeah, really...
全くだ
いや やめたんだ
No, I quit.
（ジェット）ああ そうか
Huh, I see...
Tenth day.  It's a hard world to live in for smokers, anyway.
（ファド）禁煙 10日目だ
喫煙者には住みにくい世の中だしな
（ジェット）へえー お前がね
Hmm...  I never thought you would.
で 話ってのは？
And, what was it that you wanted to tell me?
There was trouble on the prison transport ship headed for Pluto.
冥王星行きの囚人輸送船で
トラブルがあった
６時間前だ
That was six hours ago.
Apparently there was an electrical malfunction...
電子系の故障があって―
それに乗じた
囚人の反乱が起きたらしい
...the prisoners took advantage of it, and rioted.
詳しいことは分からん
I don't know the details.
（ジェット）それで？
And?
ウダイが乗ってる
Udai is on that ship.
We don't know where the ship went after it left the Ganymede Gate.
ガニメデゲートを出てから
行方がつかめん
The ISSP is frantically searching.
Ｉ.Ｓ.Ｓ.Ｐが
必死で捜索中だが…
お前 ばかな考えはよせよ
管轄外だろ？
Hey, you... don't get any stupid ideas.
It's out of your jurisdiction.
ばかな考えだと思ってるのか？
You think it's a stupid idea?
お前が警察をやめたのだって
あのときの…
The reason you quit being a cop was...
...because of when...
Now THAT is past the statute of limitations.
それこそ時効だ
If after all this, he lives on...
（ファド）このまま
あいつが生き延びたら―
...wouldn't that left arm of yours cry, Jet?
その左腕が泣かないか？ ジェット
That story doesn't interest me anymore...
今の俺には もう興味のない話さ
（ファド）
ジェット 俺はこっちから回り込む
Jet!  I'll go around from this side!
Got it!
分かった！
ウダイ･タクシム
お前を逮捕する！
Udai Taxim!
You are under arrest!
わなか？
A trap?!
What are ya gonna do?
どうする？
Ｉ.Ｓ.Ｓ.Ｐの追っ手が
すぐにも来ちまうぜ
The guys from the ISSP are gonna come any minute!
And the pilot's dead.
パイロットは おっちんじまったし
もちろん突破する
We're gonna break through, of course.
Easy for you to say.
（エルロイ）言うのは簡単だよな
We only got enough weapons for self-defense.
自衛程度の武器しかないんだぜ
どうすんだよ
What are ya gonna do?
I'm sure they've set up a barricade.
（ネロ）
やつらは網を張ってるはずだ
It would be better for us to attack...
先に こちらから仕掛けて
手薄な場所を破ったほうがいい
...and break through where they're thin.
Can you... steer this thing?
お前 操縦できるのか？
昔 金星の警察にいた
I was a cop on Venus once.
And now you're imprisoned for life?
それが今や
死刑囚ってわけかあ？
警官だって ただの人間さ
Cops are human, too...
You got back?
（エド）おかえりさーん
出掛けるぞ　危ないから下がってな
I'm heading out.
It's dangerous, so stand back.
You're going out.  Get souvenirs!
お出掛けさん　お土産ね
エド
Ed...
If I don't come back, water the bonsai for me.
俺が もし戻らなかったら
盆栽に水をやっといてくれ
Yup!
あーい
盆栽 天才 チンゲンサイ
八百八町に灯がともる
Bonsai, wise guy, chicken pot pie.
Lights shine bright in the many towns.
（ポリス）本部 応答願います
HQ, do you read?
こちらＤの７班
手配中の囚人輸送船を発見しました
This is Group D-7.
We have spotted the prison transport ship.
The ship is sending an SOS.
当該機はＳＯＳを発信中
Apparently they ran into some mechanical trouble.
機体にトラブルが
発生しているものとみられます
We are releasing a lifeboat.
（ウダイ）
これより救命ボートで投降する
On the boat are 4 officers and 12 inmates.
ボートには警官４名と
囚人12名が乗っている
We're requesting a pickup.
救出を希望する
Number 12, Number 13, no response.  We request emergency backup.
（ポリス）12 13番 応答なし
至急 応援を請う
Repeat, we request emergency backup.
繰り返す　至急 応援を請う
We have lost sight of the transport.  Current location is seven-four-five.
輸送船を見失いました
現在位置は７ ４ ５
Group D-7, initiate code ten-eight.
Ｄの７班 コード18を使用せよ
Repeat, we request emergency backup.
繰り返す　至急応援を請う
No good.
駄目だ　警察のほうも
行方が分からんらしい
Apparently the police don't know where they went, either.
What do you think their next move will be?
次は どう出ると思う？
別の船を奪うとなると―
If they are to hijack another ship...
They'll be somewhere close to their original route...
ルートから近くて隠れられる
カンショウとか
At a place where they can hide...
（ジェット）違うな
（ファド）何？
I don't think so.
What?
エウロパだ
Europa.
Europa?
エウロパだって？ 根拠は？
What makes you think that?
俺がウダイならエウロパへ戻る
If I was Udai, I would go back to Europa.
しかしウダイは もう…
But, Udai is already...
もう随分 組織とは
接触がないはずだ
He hasn't contacted the syndicate in quite a while.
He is old-fashioned.
（ジェット）やつは古い人間だ
So much that he's not the right kind of guy to live in this day and age.
この時代に生きていくには
ふさわしくないくらいのな
He'll go back.  I know it...
やつは戻るさ　俺には分かる
The Black Dog that won't let go once he bites, huh?
食らいついたら離さない
ブラック･ドッグか
OK, Europa it is.
ＯＫ エウロパだな
If you're wrong, you're paying for fuel.
違ったら燃料は お前持ちだ
Wait!  What the...  OW!
（フェイ）
わっ えっ ちょ ちょっと
ちょっと何？ あちあちあち
どこ直したっていうのよー！
What part of this is fixed!
（エド）じゅわー
うおー おー　アハハハハッ
あれ？
What's this?  Jet's gonna have a fit!
（スパイク）なんだ？ こりゃあ
ジェットが目え回すぞ
頼まれたよ
He asked me.
He's not comin' back!
帰ってこないんだって
It's okay, just bring something to wipe this up.
いいから
なんか拭くもん持ってこい
Okay!
どうなってんだ？
大事な盆栽 ほっぽっちまって
What's up with him, leaving his precious bonsai here?
Hey, Jet!  What the hell is going on?!
（フェイ）ちょっと ジェット
どうなってんのよ
It's me.
（ウダイ）私だ
You seem to have done something outrageous.
（組織の男）派手なことを
やらかしたもんだな
We need a new ship.
（ウダイ）新しい船が欲しい
（組織の男）われわれと
ウダイ･タクシムの間には
There is no further relationship between us and Udai Taxim.
もはや何の関係もない
Are you betraying me?
裏切るのか？
If you want to feel that way, go ahead.
（組織の男）
そう思いたければ思えばいい
（ウダイ）こっちには情報がある
I have information.
That threat won't work anymore.
（組織の男）
もう その脅しは通用しない
Times have changed while you were in prison.
（組織の男）時代は変わったんだよ
お前がムショにいる間にな
You win.  He's there.
（ファド）お前の勝ちだ　いたぞ
（ジェット）二手に分かれよう
俺は逆側から回り込む
We should split up.  I'll come around from the other end.
You're crazy!
ムチャだ
あの機体じゃ
ろくな武器も ついてないだろう？
That ship doesn't have any decent weapons!
You know how I work better than anyone else, right?
（ジェット）俺のやり方は
お前が一番よく知ってるだろ？
Hey, Jet...
（ファド）なあ ジェット
Why don't you quit being a bounty hunter and pair up with me again?
賞金稼ぎなんかやめて
もう一度 俺と組まないか？
I'll think about it if we get back.
戻ってきたら考えといてやるよ
（ネロ）熱源反応だ
Heat source detected.
Someone after us?
追っ手か？
If it's the ISSP, I doubt they would come alone.
Ｉ.Ｓ.Ｓ.Ｐなら
１機で来るとは考えにくい
I found something good in the cargo bay.
（エルロイ）
格納庫で いいもん見つけたぜ
And we have the perfect target.
ちょうどいいターゲットの
お出ましだ
All right, Jet...
いいか？ ジェット
このまま氷に紛れて接近する
We'll approach them using this ice for cover.  Stay there until I signal...
合図するまで
お前はそのまま…
（ファド）おっ
JET!
ジェット！
I don't know who ya are, but we'll give ya a warm welcome!
誰だか知らんが歓迎するぜ
（エルロイ）ひゅー
Here ya go!
ほらよ！
Bingo!
ビンゴ！ おっ
おああ あああ
いい度胸だぜ　１人でお出ましだ
That guy's got guts...
...to come here alone.
なんだ？ あいつ
What the hell is he?
おい どこへ？
Hey, where are you...
あれは俺の客だ
He's my visitor.
You've got to be kidding.
冗談じゃねえ
I'm not gonna put up with all of this!
付き合ってられるかよ
（荒い息）
わざわざ俺に会いに来たのか
You came all the way here to see me?
I didn't come here because I wanted to!
（ジェット）
来たくて来たわけじゃねえ！
そう言うな
せっかく出迎えに来たんだ
Don't say that, I came out here just to greet you.
来たくはなかったんだが
会いたがるやつがいてな
I didn't want to come...
...but something else wanted to see you.
何？
What?
The left arm that I lost!
なくした左腕だよ！
（ウダイ）おあああっ
What a happy camper you are.
なんて おめでたいやつだ
You never knew anything, did you?
今まで何も知らなったのか？
何だと？
What?
I wasn't the one who shot you back then.
（ウダイ）あのとき
お前を撃ったのは俺じゃない
お前の相棒さ
It was your partner.
Jet!  I'll go around from this side!
（ファド）
ジェット 俺はこっちから回り込む
Got it!
（ジェット）分かった！
It was all planned out from the beginning...
（ウダイ）あれは初めから
仕組まれていたのさ
組織にとって邪魔な存在だった
お前を消すためにな
To get rid of you, who was a threat to the syndicate.
Udai Taxim!
（ジェット）ウダイ･タクシム
お前を逮捕する！
You are under arrest!
You were long since betrayed.  You were used.
（ウダイ）
お前は とっくに裏切られ
利用されていたのさ
わなか？
A trap?!
Why did you shoot?
なぜ撃った？
Was it because he was telling the truth?
やつの言ってることが
本当だからか？
ここに来たのも
やつの口を封じるためだったのか？
You came here to shut him up for good?
Why aren't you answering me?!
なぜ答えない？
It was your fault, Jet.
お前のせいだ ジェット
お前が１人で行くから こうなった
It ended up this way because you went in on your own...
You know what happens to people who go against the syndicate, right?
組織に逆らった人間がどうなるか
分かるだろう？
Either they all quit like you... or they die.
お前みたいにやめるか
あるいは死ぬかだ
きれい事だけじゃ
生きていけないんだ
We can't live on with our pretty little ideals.
That's why you betrayed me...
（ジェット）
だから俺を裏切ったのか？
...and kept fooling me?!
俺をだまし続けたのか？
I wanted to team up with you like back then.
昔みたいにお前と
もう一度 組みたかったよ
お別れだ ジェット
Time for farewells, Jet.
（ジェット）
ファド！ ぐうっ うっ…
Fad!
Jet...
ジェット
まさか
You didn't...
お前 わざと俺に撃たせて…
Did you let me shoot on purpose?
Can I have... a smoke?
たばこを―
くれ
I guess...  I couldn't quit smoking...
禁煙―
破っちまったよ
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（アントニオ）
今回は わしら３人で
予告をやってみるかの
This time, the three of us will try to do the previews!
Do you think we can do it?
（ジョビン）
わしらに できるかの？
We only have 30 seconds!  If you're too slow, it'll all be over!
（カルロス）30秒しかないんじゃ
もたもたしとったら終わっちまうぞ
You sure are restless...
（ジョビン）せわしないのお
Anyway, what kinda story is it next time?
（アントニオ）
で 次回は どんな話なんじゃ？
（ジョビン）思い出せんのう
I can't remember...
What are you doing?!  We're already running out of time!
（カルロス）なあに やっとんじゃ
もう時間がないぞ
Come on, at least tell them the title!
（アントニオ）
タイトルだけでも言っとけ ほら
Next episode...  Wait, what was it?
（ジョビン）
次回… 何だったかの？
We couldn't do it after all!
（カルロス）やっぱ無理じゃった